[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Yeah, I'm feeling pretty good
right about now.
G-MAN: Rise and shine, Mr. Freeman.
BLAAAGH!
G-MAN: Rise and shine.
Back the fuck up!
G-MAN: Not that I wish to imply
Back it up! Keep going!
G-MAN: you have been sleeping on the job.
AAAAAH!
G-MAN: No one has been more deserving
Stop...
G-MAN: of a rest,
G-MAN: and all the effort in the world
Just stop...
G-MAN: would have gone to waste until...
Your breath smells like paint.
G-MAN: Well, let's just say
your hour has... come again.
That's close enough! Personal space!
PERSONAL SPACE, YOU FREAK!
Aaaargh!
G-MAN: The right man in the wrong place
can make all the difference in the world.
Oh, who said that? JFK?
G-MAN: So wake up, Mr. Freeman.
Maybe Churchill.
G-MAN: Wake up and smell the ashes.
Yeah, bye! Don't let me keep you!
Oh, god! Is he gone? Am I on Earth again?
Good! Well, I'm not going back.
YOU HEAR ME?! I'M NOT GOING BACK!
MAN #1: I didn't see you get on.
Yeah, where are we?
This is Hawaii, right? That was the
deal! He was going to send me to Hawaii.
This doesn't look like Hawaii.
Does Hawaii have a railway?
I think they do.
Aloha!
MAN #2: No matter how many times I've
been relocated, I never get used to it.
Okay, you're going to be a
crappy wingman. No bars for you.
I guess this is the main island.
MAN #1: End of the line.
Could be Oahu.
Okay, no greeters. This kind of sucks.
WAAAAGH! I'M BLIND! I CAN'T SEE!
HELP! HELP ME!
NO! Bl-BLAAGH! WHAT WAS THAT?!
I should've come by boat.
There's a lot of trash here.
I'm confused. What is this?
ADMINISTRATOR: ...in the Citadel
so thoughtfully provided...
This is like Max Headroom for old people.
ADMINISTRATOR: I've been proud
to call City 17 my home...
Oh, it's a timeshare infomercial.
ADMINISTRATOR: Whether you are
here to stay, or...
Or traveler's insurance or some crap.
Oh! Am I seeing things?
No!
Oh, this is perfect!
Yeah, keep sweeping, zapface! You've
got a lot of work ahead of you!
Oh, this makes my day. Next to
seeing their heads on a stick,
this is about the best thing I could've
asked for. I'm going to like this.
Knowing that we've domesticated
those things gives me some real hope.
METROCOP #1: Move away.
MAN #3: But this stuff... it's
all I have left.
MAN #3: Oof!
Oh, here we go!
MAN #3: All right. I'm moving! Jesus.
Awww...
I could watch cop fights all
day. Never gets old.
WOMAN #1: Were you the only ones
on that train?
More trash...  Uh... What?
Oh, yeah. It was just me.
It's always just me.
Hey, I get why there's so much trash.
They're leaving it for
the alien to sweep up!
Yeah, look at that. Nobody's even trying.
And you know what?
I don't blame you one bit.
MAN #4: Don't drink the water! They put
something in it... to make you forget.
MAN #4: I don't even
remember how I got here.
Hey! I don't either! What's going on?
Okay, I remember fighting an elder god,
I won because I'm that good,
then some lights flash, the CIA
spook made a deal, now I'm here.
Y'know, Time Lord or not, I think
he might be a sexual predator.
He had me completely paralyzed,
and I swear to God, I thought he
was going to French kiss me.
That was hell. That was absolute hell.
Hey, why is everyone wearing the
same clothes?
MAN #5: I'm working up the nerve to go on.
Is this a work camp or something?
Did he send me to prison?
Why would he do that?
If he wanted me dead, he could've
just left me where I was,
but he recruited me, so what's my mission?
I don't know these people.
I think I'm in the future.
That alien didn't get a job
sweeping overnight.
Oh, great. I don't even have my
ID. This is going to go well.
Yep.
All right. Uh...
Hi. I'm a political refugee seeking asylum.
My government betrayed me.
METROCOP #2: You! Citizen! Come with me.
Yes! Citizen! Exactly! I am a citizen!
Now we're getting somewhere.
MAN #6: This must be a mistake.
MAN #6: I got a standard relocation
coupon just like everybody else.
Oh yeah. Argue with bureaucracy.
Good luck with that.
Hey, I don't have an ID, but you can look
me up by Social Security number, right?
METROCOP #2: GET IN!
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, what the hell is this? You
do dental work here, too?
METROCOP #3: Need any help with this one?
METROCOP #2: No, I'm good.
The chair doesn't have any restraints.
METROCOP #2: Back up!
You'd get yourself killed trying
to torture somebody in this.
METROCOP #2: Yeah. I'm gonna
need me some privacy for this!
Okay! Guess I'm wrong!
METROCOP #2: Now...
I'll play dumb, then bash him
as hard as I can.
BARNEY: ...about that beer I owed ya.
What?
BARNEY: It's me, Gordon,
Barney from Black Mesa.
Not ringing a bell.
BARNEY: Sorry for the scare, I had
to put on a show for the cameras.
BARNEY: I've been working
undercover with Civil Protection.
BARNEY: I can't take too long or
they'll get suspicious.
BARNEY: I'm WAY behind on my beating quota.
Pervert.
KLEINER: Yes, Barney. What is it?
Oh, it's Kleiner.
KLEINER: I'm in the middle
of a critical test.
BARNEY: Sorry, doc, but look who's here.
Yo!
KLEINER: Great Scott! Gordon Freeman!
You know it!
KLEINER: I would've expected more warning.
BARNEY: Yeah, you and me both, doc.
BARNEY: He was about to board
the express to Nova Prospekt.
KLEINER: Well, Barney, what do you intend?
BARNEY: I'm thinking, I'm thinking!
KLEINER: Alyx is around here... somewhere.
KLEINER: She would have a better
idea of how to get him here.
BARNEY: Well, as long as he stays away
from checkpoints, we should be okay.
What?
BARNEY: Listen, I gotta go, doc.
We're taking enough chances as it is.
I don't know what's going on, guys.
KLEINER: Gordon, good to see you.
Respect!
BARNEY: Okay, Gordon. You're gonna have to
make your own way to Doctor Kleiner's lab.
I need an address.
[knocking]
BARNEY: Oh, man! That's what I was afraid of.
Blah!
BARNEY: Get in here, Gordon,
BARNEY: before you blow my cover.
Okay! Fine!
I don't even know what's happening.
I don't care if you get fired.
BARNEY: Get through that window and
keep going until you're in the plaza.
BARNEY: I'll meet up with you later.
So that's Kleiner's errand boy.
This makes more sense now.
Hmm. Well, I trust Kleiner... and
that's about the whole list, so...
Yeah, all right...
RAAAAAAGH!
I can only assume there's a
reason for doing this.
I'm too confused to know if I
have problems or not.
So, why is Kleiner in Hawaii?
He's probably in one of the observatories
trying to pinpoint where the
aliens came from.
Did the CIA grab him, too?
METROCOP #4: Pick up that can.
Oh! Is this what I think it is?
METROCOP #4: Now.
Put it... in the trash can.
Ah! I see my reputation precedes me!
All right.
How about from here? This is good.
Easy.
METROCOP #4: All right. You can
go. Heh heh...
You know how many sodas I drank in college?
Seriously, I'm the master.
Hey, was that on camera? No...
I could've made that shot
blindfolded. I'm not even joking.
I've thrown thousands of soda cans.
I got my degree under the
tutelage of Dr. Pepper.
Oh, a food line.
Well, I don't have an ID so that's out.
I'll just steal something later.
There's too many cops here.
It's best to grab it out of
somebody's hand on the street
because they'll chase you, but they won't
file a report over a stolen hot dog.
Ooookaaay... this is definitely not Hawaii.
Yeah, they fucked me. The CIA fucked me.
What's that lettering? Is this
Russia? Eastern Europe? Dammit.
So I have no money, no ID, and
I'm lost in another country.
What a great plan this was.
Well, I'm just going to have to
hustle my way out of this.
Yeah, you'll do.
A-ahem.
Hey, girl! How you doin'?
WOMAN #2: If I talk to you out
here, we'll both be in trouble.
What the hell? What's going on?
Desperate women love me.
[sighs]
This is a complete shit show.
The CIA creep said he had an
important job for me.
You know what would've helped?
Knowing what my job is?
What's this? A Gestapo raid?
Yeah! Great place to drop me
with no information!
I'm surprised he didn't send me here naked.
[thumping] That really would--
[thumping]
[thumping] Oh my god. It's a Tripod.
It's a fucking Tripod!
Uh... I gotta get out of here.
They're real! How did we-- No,
I'll figure it out later.
I've gotta hide. This explains a lot.
Well, they're not Capping me.
I'll kill everyone in this city
before I let that happen.
Tripods...
That must be where these friggin'
servo-skulls came from, too.
Everything's changed.
Hey, are you two Capped? How do
you live with yourselves?
MAN #7: This is how it always starts.
First the building, then the whole block.
MAN #8: They have no reason to
come to our place.
More cops...
MAN #7: Don't worry, they'll find one.
Well, they don't sound Capped. I guess
that means I don't have to kill them.
I need a gun.
Well, Kleiner's here, so I guess I'll
hide out until his lackey gets off work
then find out where he is,
because it would've killed him to take
three seconds to give me an address.
Nobody knows what they're doing.
I see THAT hasn't changed.
Yeah, what was his name? Barney?
I did find it kind of hilarious how
he's like, "It's me from Black Mesa."
[lock buzzes]
Dammit, not this way.
I mean we had, what, 15,000
employees at that facility alone?
He's talking like we're best
friends. I don't even remember him.
"It's me, Gordon, from General Electric."
Oh, more cops.
Great. I feel safer all ready.
Maybe there's a roof access up here.
METROCOP #5: Get moving.
Oh. Hi.
No go on the stairs. So now what?
Man, fuck the CIA!
You know what the problem is? We
didn't negotiate.
All I said was "Hawaii",
but I would've taken Jamaica,
Cayman Islands, anything like that.